<resources>
    <string name="app_name">QUIZ</string>

    <string name="welcomeTitle">Welcome to quiz about Poland</string>
    <string name="welcomeMessage">This is a test of knowledge about Poland. Here you will find questions from the category of geography and famous Poles.</string>

    <string name="error">No answer selected.</string>
    <string name="errorMessage">Please select the answer</string>


    <string name="text_question1">Where is Poland?</string>
    <string name="answer1_1">In Africa</string>
    <string name="answer1_2">In Asia</string>
    <string name="answer1_3">In Europe</string>

    <string name="text_question2">Does Poland have access to the sea?</string>
    <string name="answer2_1">Yes</string>
    <string name="answer2_2">No</string>

    <string name="text_question3">How many lakes are there in Poland?</string>
    <string name="answer3_1">One thousand and fifty-eight</string>
    <string name="answer3_2">Almost ten thousand</string>
    <string name="answer3_3">Less than one thousand</string>

    <string name="text_question4">Are mountains in Poland?</string>
    <string name="answer4_1">Yes</string>
    <string name="answer4_2">No</string>

    <string name="text_question5">The best known Polish football player (currently)</string>
    <string name="answer5_1">Łukasz Podolski</string>
    <string name="answer5_2">Robert Lewandowski</string>
    <string name="answer5_3">Arkadiusz Milik</string>

    <string name="text_question6">Who was Fryderyk Chopin</string>
    <string name="answer6_1">Flutist</string>
    <string name="answer6_2">Violinist</string>
    <string name="answer6_3">Pianist</string>

    <string name="text_question7">What Maria Sklodowska-Curie discovered?</string>
    <string name="answer7_1">Oxygen and hydrogen</string>
    <string name="answer7_2">Polon and rad</string>
    <string name="answer7_3">X rays</string>

    <string name="text_question8">Who was Karol Wojtyla?</string>
    <string name="answer8_1">Pianist</string>
    <string name="answer8_2">Well-known vocalist</string>
    <string name="answer8_3">Pope (John Paul II)</string>

    <string name="text_question9">Who was Nicolaus Copernicus</string>
    <string name="answer9_1">An astronomer, mathematician and doctor</string>
    <string name="answer9_2">Musician, composer</string>
    <string name="answer9_3">An IT specialist known by the programist</string>

    <string name="submit">Submit</string>

    <string name="description1">
        <b>Poland</b> (Polish: Polska), officially the Republic of Poland (Polish: Rzeczpospolita Polska), is a sovereign country in Central Europe. \n \n
        It is covering an area of 312,679 square kilometres  with a mostly temperate climate.\n \n
        With a population of over 38.5 million people, Poland is the sixth most populous member state of the European Union.\n \n
        Poland\'s capital and largest city is Warsaw. Other cities include Kraków, Łódź, Wrocław, Poznań and Gdańsk.
    </string>

    <string name="description2">
        <b>The territory of Poland is located by the Baltic Sea</b>, which is located in the north of the country. The beaches are wide and sandy.
    </string>

    <string name="description3">
        With almost ten thousand closed bodies of water covering more than 1 hectare (2.47 acres) each, <b>Poland has one of the highest numbers of lakes in the world</b>. In Europe,
        only Finland has a greater density of lakes.
    </string>

    <string name="description4">
        In the south of Poland there are mountains, which are taken by the <b>Sudetes and Carpathians</b>. The Tatra Mountains located along the southern Polish border
        are the highest part of the Carpathians.\n \n
        The highest mountain in Poland, Rysy at 2.503 m, is located in the High Tatras.
    </string>

    <string name="description5">
        <b>Robert Lewandowski</b> (born 21 August 1988 in Warsaw, Poland) is a Polish association football striker who plays for Bayern Munich and the Poland national football team.\n \n
    </string>

    <string name="description6">
        <b>Fryderyk Franciszek Chopin</b> was a Polish-French composer and virtuoso pianist. He is considered one of the greatest Romantic piano composers.\n \n
        Chopin was born in Żelazowa Wola, a village in the Duchy of Warsaw.
    </string>

    <string name="description7">
        <b>Marie Skłodowska–Curie</b> was a Polish and French physicist, chemist and feminist. She did research on radioactivity.
        As a result of her research, she discovered polonium and radium.
        She was the first person to win two Nobel Prizes.She received a Nobel Prize in physics for her research on uncontrolled radiation.\n \n
    </string>

    <string name="description8">
        <b>Karol Józef Wojtyła, Pope John Paul II</b>was the 264th Pope of the Catholic Church from 16 October 1978 to his death in 2005.\n \n
        He was the second longest-serving pope in history. As a Pole, he was the first non-Italian pope in 455 years.\n
         He was the first ever pope to visit the White House and a mosque. \n
         John Paul II was canonized by Pope Francis on April 27, 2014.
    </string>

    <string name="description9">
        <b>Nicolaus Copernicus</b> was a mathematician and astronomer who formulated a model of the universe that placed the Sun rather than the
        Earth at the center of the universe.\n \n
        A polyglot and polymath, he obtained a doctorate in canon law and was also a mathematician, astronomer, physician, classics scholar, translator,
        governor, diplomat, and economist. In 1517 he derived a quantity theory of money – a key concept in economics.
    </string>

    <string name="good">Your answer is good</string>
    <string name="bad">Your answer is bad</string>

    <string name="end">The end of the quiz</string>

    <string name="text_range1">
        \n \n I think your knowledge about Poland is not very good. I hope that the comments on the questions allowed you to deepen
        your knowledge about Poland. It will be better next time.
    </string>

    <string name="text_range2">
       \n \n Very good result. You have a lot of knowledge about Poland. A few questions made you difficult. I hope that the descriptions
        provided have allowed you to deepen your knowledge about Poland.
    </string>

    <string name="text_range3">
        \n \n Excellently. Your knowledge about Poland concerns both its history and current times. I think you could be a guide in my country.
    </string>


</resources>
